nothing quite says christmas like a
santa gast
this is probably the best thing i've
seen in hermitcraft season 6 and that's
saying something i don't know who's
responsible for this dare i say it piece
of art and i also don't know how it
works
why isn't he going
you know what we could do we could put a
resource pack on to make this gas go ho
ho ho
how does this work
uh okay so there's it's inside a
minecart
and there's loads of glass there
that is amazing
well anyway hello welcome back to
another episode of hermitcraft yes i'm
still dead and we are here
in the christmas district because we
need to grab ourselves a secret santa
from santa's sleigh of course it is
christmas coming up very very soon so
sorry to those of you that are watching
in the future let's see who we get
b-dubs
we managed to get b-dubs we got b-dubs
okay so what present are they going to
get
so this is by the way this is the
present that we have to give them and i
hope they haven't been naughty so we got
b-dub and we have to cover their base in
custom paintings oh my goodness this is
perfect can i cover it in pictures of my
face
yeah okay so it's gonna take me a little
while to get this resource pack made
because i'm gonna need all sorts of
custom art and pictures and paintings
and all that stuff and i know just the
guy so hopefully it'll be ready by the
end of the episode because it usually
takes me a few days and then we'll go to
vw's base and we will plaster these
paintings everywhere um so it's gonna be
really interesting so hopefully we can
get that done later
so for now let's carry on with the rest
of the episode because we've got quite a
few things that we need to do not least
trying to get demise all wrapped up
and there are only a few people left in
fact why don't we go over to the big
demise board and actually check who's
alive and who's gone
who did that
who has done this
who is responsible for this
unbelievable
the the cheek
i don't know how up to date this is i'm
pretty sure it's up to date okay so that
seems about right there we are i'm dead
the dead team
are outweighing the living and we have
doc mumbo i think that's joe's face we
got dubs is
gal
still alive
so we can't go after iska we can't go
after mumbo we can't go after b dubs
because of the secret bro pact so that
leaves doc and joe
joe is difficult to get because
he doesn't have a base
and
like yeah it's kind of his whole thing
he's a bit of a nomad doc does have a
little project and it's over here
somewhere
but actually while we're here why don't
we go and see what happened with
corrales
so here we are and yep it's been
triggered absolutely destroyed um
all the puffer fish are of course gone
and yeah it definitely killed him the
thing is he had already died
and mrs puff got him so not only did mrs
puff get him and i'm out a hundred
diamonds i haven't actually got many
diamonds left
but i also didn't even get the kill
because corrales had already died to
mumbo's trap or something something to
do with tango's trap and collab with
mumbo so yeah it
it worked it definitely worked but it um
it also kind of didn't work at the same
time but corrales has officially demised
so
now let's go over to where doc is
working and oh
my
goodness this is absolutely insane
seriously this is so whoa
look at this from the bottom this looks
absolutely so impressive but i see no
obvious way to trap this either there's
something up here
but
even this doesn't look super trappable i
don't really know what this is i think
you might have to afk somewhere which we
could trap
hmm
this would definitely be the obvious
place to trap doc
if we could figure this out it could
work
i see no easy way to trap this so we
might have to wait for doc to get online
because i have a small plan on how we
can get him but i actually have to wait
for him to get on so basically we can't
do much until doc or joe come
online and then we can get on with our
demise plans
so let's head on back to sahara where
we're still trying to get our hands on
enough stock
we've got loads and loads of stuff to do
and it's not the ah
come on
who put that there
no
come on this is
ridiculous all right it's not the end of
the world i can just walk all the way
along here
we can put the
stupid blocks
oh finally
i'm not exaggerating that took so long
to walk here
oh man
i know i was like jokingly grumbling but
the more i went along the more genuine
my grumbling got
by by by the end of it i was just
genuinely like
oh
three minutes of walking just because of
that stupid glass
now that happened because of my new set
of armor
it's of course i died and none of them
have the normal protection they've all
got blast protection on because i
couldn't be bothered to get all the
books for them so yeah i took way more
damage than i really needed to but
whatever it's not a big deal
so let's take a quick look in the stock
room and
nothing has really changed but some
people have claimed some things there's
some there's some
slime block and mumbo's got this for
bone blocks and he's taking the uh i i
guess i'll take the dispensers then
um so yeah sea lanterns that's got to be
escals as well
yeah i guess i could take care of
dispensers it's just the worst it's just
the worst to craft up but the real
question is how do i make my chair even
bigger
i think we can but i'd have to sort of
break into the wall um but yeah no one's
really putting up much of a fight so
might yeah it's got to stay like that
for a while
right so let's go and craft ourselves up
a bunch of dispensers
for the next part of the stocking of
sahara which means getting a lot of
string and then
this is going to be one of the most
boring things that i ever do on
hermitcraft i've done it before so i i'm
speaking from experience
oh my goodness
oh my goodness i'm i may not have to
craft that many at all i've forgot about
all of these redstone boxes that i had
from impulse and there's a bunch of
dispensers in here
okay there's droppers
all right maybe there's more droppers
than dispensers in here but that
i forgot about this
that could be good
either way let me show you why this is a
pain okay it's not the actual dispenser
it's the to do with the bows so bows
don't stack that's the problem so you
basically have to craft these
individually one by one and you've got
to click each one twice
okay
we're about to go on a crafting
adventure now this is going to be so
boring we're going to do this in a
time-lapse style we're going to we're
going to time-lapse this just because i
spent an hour doing this
and i'm going to put the most crazy
music to make this scene more
interesting than it is three two one
let's go
[Music]
okay so we have got ourselves some
dispensers and by some
this is a lot okay this is really a lot
of dispensers and
i know it really doesn't look like it
that's the main thing but it was a well
over an hour of clicking so 64
times two clicks that's a lot of clicks
either way we're putting i've had enough
of dispensers for now that is it i'm i'm
not i am not crafting up any more
dispensers
this is going over here into the stock
oh wow look at the progress that's
happened iskall has been on it we got
some sand we got redstone we got rock
rock we can make so many more rockets
than that that that one there should be
all the way up to the end anyway look at
the progress i mean this has been
there's been a a real project to get
sahara stocked up again but if we can
increase this to max and i should
probably actually
make more because um this is only like
half the stock list actually there's
there's quite a few more so i'm probably
going to have to make another another
board full of items and then his gala
mambo are not going to be happy about it
but it's going to take us a little while
to get everything stocked up
but we won't worry about that for now
shall we because as you may have just
seen doc went to bed he is online
meaning now is my opportunity
to execute my final demise plan
what we're going to do is we're going to
follow doc around potentially for hours
potentially for five minutes which is
why we can't hang around too long i need
to go and get a lot of materials very
very quickly particularly
some very dastardly materials and i'm
hoping that i've got some around here
there we go this is what we need
lava buckets everywhere this is
absolutely perfect now i don't think
anyone's done this but what we're going
to do is we're going to stalk doc
up until
he logs out and then we're going to trap
the exact location that he logs out on
the main issue is i need to get my hands
on on some obsidian asap pronto before
he logs out he might be streaming let me
just check if he's streaming okay i
haven't got a single bit of obsidian so
uh i've got a place where i usually go
to for obsidian but it's not exactly the
the best
it's right down here
okay we've got to get our hands on like
30 obsidian as quickly as possible
before doc logs out doc's still online
i'm just slowly getting obsidian the
last thing i want is to run out of
obsidian halfway through making a box
okay i think we've definitely got enough
now
let's head over back to where doc was
working on his raid farm and i've got
myself a couple of invisibility potions
just in case because here's the thing
we're gonna have to get quite close
there better not be any there not be any
more things in the way here
seriously annoying because it doesn't
load fast enough you can't even react
okay so
we are round about the area i don't
actually know if doc's there the first
thing is to confirm that doc is actually
where i think he is
okay so
can we see him
we're going to have to get closer i
think we may need to go full incognito
because my name tag is going to be the
first thing that gives me away let's get
rid of that with invisibility potion
so the next thing that will give me away
is the sound of the rockets
and i've learned the distance quite well
so what i'm gonna do is fly really high
over the top of the raid farm and guess
whereabouts it is there it is there it
is
if i take my armor off
it's just a pair of elytra in the air
okay so i know roughly where
his base is there okay so if i fly over
it i can't see him
there he is there he is he's afk he's
okay all right we have confirmed the
location
of
dark
m77 so if we land
very surreptitiously
i think we've got a successful landing
right here
now if i have nothing in my hand
only potion particles are giving me away
now i gotta be
careful with my parkour i almost fell
oh it is a raid farm there's
there's pillages unless they're just
random pillages okay there he is
he's up there now we could be here
a very very long time
he's doing building
so i think we could potentially just
stay here for a little while
but like i said
this could be
easily a couple of hours of waiting but
i'm prepared to do it the problem is
i've got i've got five minutes 32 and
i've got another invisibility potion on
me
so the issue here
is not the fact that i'm running out of
time the fact is i need to know exactly
where he's going to log out and for that
i actually need to be really really
close otherwise i'm just guessing
and then there's nothing he can do he's
he has he has no idea
so if he logs out and i can't see where
on this thing he is i'm in big trouble
so in that case
he is he
he could be looking right at me he has
no idea he has got a total of undying
but what if i was able i need to get up
there so i can see exactly where he logs
out
okay here we are we've made it we made
it we made it out
that sound could have given me away
nothing in my hand totally invisible
completely invisible where'd he go aha
this is perfect
that might did he hear that
okay so now it's just a waiting game
one issue that we have is i've got two
minutes 49 of invisibility
and i'm going to have to drink this
when it runs out or the game might be
given away
and do you know the noise that it makes
when you drink in potion it's not like
glob glub and that's it
yeah
he's he will know if someone is drinking
next to him
i think we're gonna be here a little
while
so i could just crouch here without a
potion for a while
okay i've got 45 seconds i'm gonna
parkour
if i fall i die and the jig is up
okay i'm probably far enough away
you hear how loud it is when you drink
in minecraft now i got a parkour back
here
doc has no idea
oh
she was just re-logging i thought i'd
missed it i thought i'd missed it
okay keep an eye on him
man i really think that we could end up
being here quite a while i mean i've
already been here about 16 minutes i
have officially run out of invisibility
potion i've got nothing got nothing left
fortunately
it doesn't look like he's
going to look up anytime soon
but i have to keep watching otherwise he
could just log out at any moment
i've got to keep watching although i'm
pretty sure he's going to finish this at
least so i think we might be safe for a
little while but if i just stay like
this as long as he doesn't fly up in the
air i think we're gonna be good
he's he's almost finished he's he's
almost done which means
he might be logging out any second and
i've been out of invisibility potion for
quite some time in fact i'm actually
going to put this back on all this stuff
just in case i manage to fall
it won't actually kill me
this has been the longest stakeout
possible
okay it's just restocking oh there's a
there's a zombie after you
[Laughter]
but he is going to end up back there
okay okay i need to stop playing with
fire and just wait just be patient just
be patient
just be patient
oh very good for a second there i
thought he was coming up here
we've officially been here for about 45
minutes now
so i've actually had time you know i've
been having a drink i've been having
lily
i'm so surprised he hasn't seen me yet
but i have been hopping and skipping
there's been some pretty close calls
over the last 45 minutes i've had to hop
around there some major parkour
oh did he see me did he did he see me
i've got to basically
as scar would say i'm a dodging i'm a
weavin
come on doc
if you've finished it's done
what could you possibly want to do more
the longer i sit here waiting
the more of a bad idea this seems
wait where's he going no no no no no no
doc
where are you going
i need to get i need to get closer
i need to get closer
he's
oh wait he's not coming back up is he
he's getting absolutely wrecked
man
look at all the errors in him
the adventures of someone playing
minecraft who doesn't know that they're
being watched
every everyone has now seen you just get
absolutely wrecked by a skeleton
get him punch him get him get him get
him punch him he's a guy
oh no
oh he's probably gonna look up from that
he's probably gonna look up we're going
to take that off
at least i'm nice and gray he's going to
build it back all the way up uh time to
time to vamoose time to time to vamoose
time to vomit this is going to be a
close call okay i see him
is that it
oh my goodness
okay
how
oh man
he logged out right
there right there that's one
two
three
four five
it's about seven blocks from that torch
that's not gonna be easy to remember
you're joking
come on
i forgot to put my stuff back
on oh
well i'm alone on the server now so it
doesn't matter
oh my goodness
quickly
before it's too late
this is the worst oh this is the worst
stakeout that i've ever seen in my life
the timing of that was unbelievable i'm
pretty sure i did have my armor on i
just
i just died instantly
let's remember where we were so we were
looking down
yeah that torch and it was about there
this is why we brought lots of
this is why we brought lots of things
with us
okay so it was this torch here and it
was about one two three four five six
seven
roughly he was like doing this i think
he was possibly doing his outro right
here
so in theory
right here but um
i'm gonna make like a safety net square
to make sure that
that's correct
oh look it's the cursed portal i don't
know how he did this still
okay
right so this is it we need to get our
obsidian ready and then all of our lava
buckets and we can set up and get going
on this before he logs back on he could
be back on any second to do his work
here
okay so we need to remove this
and we need a good safety net okay so
we'll put it one block down to be sure
and then wall up
here
this is such a simple trap but it means
i
i don't think doc saw me he definitely
didn't look at me at any point but this
is a genius trap it's just actually
really difficult to execute mainly
because you've just got to wait such a
long time
so basically he won't have any choice
but to perish in here unless he's got
one of these wait yeah a fire potion a
potion of fire resistance i think he's
pretty much done for so i've got my uh
potion of fire resistance on
and we're going to get this all lathered
up
thank goodness doc hasn't been online
because seriously this has taken over 20
minutes so if he was just logging off
for like the toilet or something i would
be i would be absolutely ruined here
okay i've still got my fire resistance
on
just going to seal this up except for
here
and we are going to make sure there's no
air pockets because he might if he's
really really quick he might be able to
figure a way out of this i'm not sure
how
either he's got a fire resistance potion
or something but
it doesn't seem to me like there's any
way out i think if he makes his way out
of this he definitely deserves he does
he deserves to live on this one and i
think it really doesn't matter where you
go
and because you're in lava you can't
swing your pickaxe as much i don't know
i can't actually get out of here
there we go okay
right there we go sealing that up now
because there's such a small chance that
if he's like uh he might be like in this
corner or in this corner here and it
might just like spawn him when he logs
back in it might just put him here
because it thinks the blocks are full so
i'm going to put a safety layer
of dirt all the way around
just to make sure that the game if i've
got my location slightly off
will default him into the obsidian box
now i do feel kind of bad because
this this what happened to me when i
died was i lost all of my items now
that's really like it's just a mild
inconvenience but it's easily like an
hour's worth of work to get your stuff
back
so that gives me a little idea
once we've got this up we're gonna we're
gonna go get something for doc
we've got ourselves a safety box and the
chances are he's gonna spawn right in
there with all that lava but actually we
need to make a quick drop off back to
the island and then back here again so
give me one sec and i'll be there here
we are no one has taken this
it is one of the original did you die
boxes volume one two stacks of diamonds
there's it's not got the best uh god
armor here and but that doesn't matter
because uh doc doc only really needs
this stuff here which is the tools this
is going to be excellent and then the
elytra and then you know you know what a
did you die box is we will rename this
to
did you
demise and then we're going to leave
that
on top of the obsidian box if someone
had offered me a did you die box in fact
i'm surprised i i didn't think of that
this did you die box when i lost all my
stuff i'm i'm like chock full out i
haven't got any more so i'm surprised i
didn't think of this but i would have
bought this in a second after i died
because it was a nightmare getting all
my stuff back here we go
did you demise
only 100 diamonds that's how much i need
to pay scar back
korean
i am giving him a discount in all
fairness i'm giving him a nice discount
on all of these goodies i'm being pretty
confident that this is gonna work but i
just have a feeling that he was around
here even if he was in the obsidian i'm
pretty sure he would glitch into the
lava we're gonna have to see i'm not
entirely sure
okay
that is done we have officially done our
second demise trap
this is dastardly and hopefully we'll
make another 100 diamonds okay so the
last thing to do is my secret santa
which i am very glad to say has been
completed by my very good friend rowan
artifex and
he has put together a nice resource pack
which he tells me is full of green
goodies which i don't know what that
means so we're about to find out helps
if i fly in the right direction there we
go so we need to go over
to
bdubs his castle which i would say
is his base at the moment
and we have to cover it in custom
paintings
this is actually very difficult to cover
in custom paintings because it's all
diagonals and
not a lot of flat surfaces i think we
just got to go for it anyway
first of all let's take a look at what
has been made
oh there we go
all right we got a poultry man
not all of them are done oh we got a
villager green
korean was here okay we got some
graffiti
we're gonna have to work we're gonna
have to work quite hard to get the exact
ones i think
what is that what is that
walking green doesn't is not real he
kind of so he's put some green memes in
there oh that's from the mumbo-proof
house oh my goodness this is amazing
okay so i'm gonna need a lot of sticks
and a lot of paintings to get this put
together
there's probably more as well oh there's
more graffiti
okay
so there's a good sample of what we're
going to be doing
to b dubs house
so let's get cracking
yeah i'm pretty happy with that also
danny
why have you done a chicken with a
what's this
why is there a chicken with a with a
little hat here
that's so weird
but that does the trick we've got some
graffiti we've got some mugs we got
whoever that is we've got villager green
green was here i think that is gonna
have to do even though there's about
three stacks of paintings on this
building you can't really tell that it
doesn't actually cover that much
my favorite one and it's probably the
rarest one is this one super weird
anyway thank you daddy for making this
resource pack i've now sent this to
bdubs he doesn't really know what it is
but we actually need to give him just a
little bit of information
christmas
you'll never guess who it was
so merry christmas from your secret
santa you'll never guess who it was yeah
you'll never guess who it was
okay so that is pretty much it for
today's episode we got a lot done
actually we've set up our demise trap we
have restocked some sahara stuff with
the dispensers
but most importantly we have delivered
our secret santa to be dubs
and he's got a well his present was um a
little bit on the naughty side he's been
naughty this year so he has got
paintings
all over his base
thank you very much for watching
everyone
and good
bye